

Address: Arbroath, UK

Email: fraser.burns@hotmail.co.uk | Telephone: +44 744 982 9405

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly passionate individual with 13 Years of Quality Control Inspection Experience. For the previous 6 months I have been working as a Goods In Inspector & have been actively involved with setting up new processes and procedures & continuous improvement projects, working with various departments on site. Previously I was working with an Additive Manufacturing (AM) Team at Baker Hughes. This period of my career provided me with a great perspective on Production/Manufacturing. I believe my experience, skill set & goals make me a perfect fit for your team

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Lab Eng – Baker Hughes: Created an Inventory Management Application that benefitted the department & business £50k a year. This Application has been requested by other sites for use.

Lab Eng – Baker Hughes: Worked alongside various customers to ensure that Additive Manufacturing was utilised correctly, accumulating to £600k a year in benefits.

QC - Baker Hughes: Created an Application for the Goods In QC Team. The Application captured all information that was required for the department. Due to functionality of the Application, the result was increased productivity & greater documentation traceability.

Pacson Valves: Highlighted material wastage that was costing the company £6k+ monthly.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

01/2024 - Present

Goods In Inspector, Sulzer GT Aero

- Perform Dimensional Inspection on Gas Turbine Engine Components Returning from Field Service, Overhauled Components & Stock Components.
- Interpret technical drawings, specifications & overhaul manuals.
- Create Purchase Requests for Parts that require repairs/overhauls
- Assist with setting up new a new Goods In Inspection department, advise on equipment requirements & process changes required
- Create a PowerApps application for the Quality & Engineering Teams to facilitate better communication & workflow between the two departments
- Implemented a new process for non-conforming products coming into the Goods In Department
- Various Continuous Improvement projects that would affect multiple departments throughout the workshop
- Update computer tracking system as inspection is complete & progress components to ensure they are fit for build

06/2022 - 10/2023

Lab Engineer, Baker Hughes

- Planning, Operating & Maintaining the 3D-Printing farm located on site
- Handle 3D-Printing requests from customers (RFQ to Delivery)

- Design additive manufacturing suitable parts to suit customers' needs
- Work with the site to provide support for the Continuous Improvement Program
- Conduct material assessments, both internally & externally to develop an additive materials database
- Supporting research & development initiatives related to digitization & sustainability through additive manufacturing technology
- Frequently interact with Suppliers & Customers
- Performing component measurement & inspection (CMM, Romer, etc)
- Managed and monitored project budget, ensuring cost-effective allocation of resources and adherence to financial constraints
- Ensure H&S Policy compliance, SOP & risk assessments was adhered to & updated accordingly within the lab
- Assist other sites/departments with Digital Solutions (VR, AR, Applications)
- Mentoring New Starts on Site

06/2018 - 06/2022

Goods In Quality Control Inspector, Baker Hughes

- Perform Dimensional Inspection on Raw Material, Finished Components & Assemblies.
- Perform MRB Review on Raw Material, Finished Components & Assemblies.
- Operation & Programming CMM
- Program & Operation of Romer & Faro Arms including creating Measurement Plans & Macros
- Programs & Operation of Leica Laser Tracker
- Utilize Augmented-Reality to assist with inspection of fabrication products using Faro Visual Inspect
- Program & Operate Keyence Optical Comparator
- Perform Alignments in T&A through the use of a Leica Laser Tracker
- Raise NCRs & assist with investigations whilst also providing feedback on preventative measures
- Actively engaged with the Inspection/Metrology industry to be aware of any new equipment that could be beneficial
- Actively participate in the Continuous Improvement Program
- Mentoring New Starts on Site

06/2016 - 06/2018

NDE Quality Control Inspector, Pacson Valves

- ASNT Level II MT & PT
- Adhered to strict oil & gas industry engineering & quality codes/standards such as API 6A/17D and ISO 9001
- Dimensional inspection using wide variety of inspection tooling including the CMM & Faro Arms
- Document Review For Incoming Goods
- Hardness Testing (Rockwell & Brinell)
- PMI Testing
- Copper Sulfate & Ferroxyl Testing
- Maintain calibration system for the site

01/2016 - 06/2016

Quality Tester, Bonar Yarns

- Perform tests to determine material tensile strength, tenacity, lubrication content, dTex & shrinkage
- Participate in investigations for non-conforming product
- Work closely with shop floor to carry out patrol inspection on product currently being manufactured

06/2011 - 10/2015

Quality Control Inspector, GA Engineering (Scotland)

- Dimensional Inspection using wide variety of inspection tooling including the CMM & Faro Arm
- Program & Operate CMM to allow a much Leaner process
- Maintain calibration system for the site
- Perform Internal Audits as per ISO 9001 Standard

WORK RELATED TRAINING

Level 3 Spatial Analyzer Training – Hexagon Metrology
Level 1 CMM Training – Hexagon Metrology
GD&T Training – Hexagon Metrology
XRF Safety Training
Materialise Magics Training
AlBuild Training
Virtalis Developer Training

EDUCATION

Present

HNC Mechanical Engineering Edinburgh College

04/2021

IOSH Managing Safely Montrose Learning Academy

06/2009 - 06/2010

NQ Practical Engineering Perth College UHI

SOFTWARE

- PC-DMIS SOLIDWORKS CREO SpatialAnalyzer (SA) Inspire Diavite AG Trimos-WinDHI
- Microsoft O365 Microsoft Power Platform Aberlink3D ANSYS Granta Mi Instron Bluehill CSAM

SKILLS

- Working with Technology Attention To Detail Continuous Improvement Mentoring
- Problem Solving Understanding Technical Drawings Taking initiative

PERSONAL INTERESTS

• 3D Printing • CAD Design • Home Automation • Programming • Android Studio

REFERENCES ON REQUEST